I kind of want to vent to y'all a little
bit. This is going to be like a quick
one. I just want to
This whole thing that's happening with
um Amanda Seales and Issa Rae. Like
I'mma come back to it, I think. I think
I'mma talk about it.
Um
How do I address this?
I feel like I should say I should
preface this with
I am immensely grateful, fortunate, and
highly blessed, right? Like and I I want
to acknowledge that I feel like it's
appropriate that you could be both
blessed
and know that there's more for you,
right? Like
And listening to like Amanda Seales cuz
she kind of like she fake crashed out
pretty recently. It's I don't want to
call it a crash out cuz she this is
whole back and forth. I guess we'll make
this a we'll make this a chat, right?
She was talking about
What's this lady's name? Issa Rae,
right?
This whole conversation about Issa Rae
and being left off the tour and all that
other stuff. And I kind of mentioned it
briefly in my last joint.
And then picking that up, she she came
back, right? And she says that people
been saying that she's jealous of Issa.
And this is like her response. I guess
I'll drop the clip in here.
>> my whole goddamn life for some for some
random [ __ ] on this internet to talk
about I'm struggling in my career. Talk
about I'm jealous of Issa Rae. Baby,
Issa Rae managed to get her own series
on television.
I remember when we were when we first
met in person in 20
I think it was 2014 and and and Insecure
was still on the shelf.
And she was like, "I'm just so
frustrated that I you know I can't get
them to to make it."
And thankfully, she was able to get it
made.
I have nothing but respect for the
ability to get something from your mind
onto the page and onto the screen.
I'm an icon.
When I was a child, I was on an iconic
black TV show on Nickelodeon. When I see
people saying
Amanda Seales is struggling in her
career, I'm looking around like,
baby,
I was ONLY THE SECOND BLACK WOMAN IN THE
history of HBO to have a COMEDY SPECIAL,
WHICH BY THE WAY is absolutely absurd.
I'm an icon.
I was on the first season and the second
season of Def Poetry Jam. I'M AN ICON.
LIKE, WHAT ARE WE TALKING ABOUT?
I've been on Q-Tip albums.
I have opened for Paul Mooney, Chris
Rock, and Dane Cook
and I'm an icon.
Don't ever get it twisted that just
because I'm here hanging out with y'all,
that I'm in a struggle. I have time.
Because I'm retired.
I divested from Hollywood.
Okay?
I was on five seasons, the complete
series of an iconic television show.
People have compared my character
Tiffany the way I played it in the same
space as Whitley Gilbert.
Dwayne, I'm an icon. Here's Insecure.
These are my shoes that Tiffany wore at
her baby shower. Here are some of our
scripts from over the season.
Uh this was uh my table card on the last
table read that we did. Here's a ticket
from uh the first episode, the first
like the premiere for the first season.
Here's some pictures from the, uh, the
party that we they had for the release
party, the premiere party. There's me
and my lovely husband, Zerrick.
AKA Wade Allain Marcus. Here's some
photos of me and my bestie, Kiki, from,
uh, these HBO parties that they would
have every year, HBO Emmy parties. Uh,
Jill Scott was riding with us one year,
so there we go, me, Jilly from Philly,
and Kiki.
Um, my mom made this for me when I got
nominated for an NAACP Award. There's a
picture of me, uh, in the Nickelodeon
studios when I was
12.
>> And
it's this whole thing. And one of the
points of the video that she shared that
stood out to me was that
while she despises or does not like Issa
Rae at this point,
Insecure still a high point of her life.
And like she holds on to the
memorabilia. So while her mouth says one
thing, her collectibles inside of her
crib suggests that this was an important
time in her life, right? And I'm sure
that people will look at that and say,
"Well, she was the one that did the work
and all this other stuff and blah blah
blah." And I it's I'm not taking away
from that, but that opportunity or that
fixture in your life
is a result of the person that you claim
that you don't like, right? So if that
person can create such a grand or
special opportunity for you, how do you
have the capacity to not like them or or
be so outrageously vocal
about who they are, what they do at the
times in which their career
is making pinnacle moments, such as her
going on this tour and you feeling the
need to hash out the fact that you don't
like her and then you were excluded from
this time.
Thinking about that [ __ ] made me think
about like
my own work experiences, right? And
the idea that there's certain people
that have truly perfected having a
problem.
Like there's some people that by
definition are insatiable. Like they'll
always have an issue with something.
They always want to bring something up.
They always going to tell you that you
need to change, adjust, and so on and so
forth. And
I've been kind of like tired and
annoyed.
I got a story for y'all.
>> [laughter]
>> So, I'm in the process of like
helping this team
grow their team, right?
I tell y'all I'm in HR, so there's a
certain level of experience and exposure
that I have that tends to be useful.
But, most people underestimate
the capacity of HR, where they've been,
and what they can do, and so on and so
forth. Now, typically there's a lot of
conversation about how HR isn't your
friend and all this other stuff, and
I'mma tell you straight no chaser like
as a person that got into HR like I I
came into HR on some Batman [ __ ] Like
it so
I had a a boss that was a [ __ ] that got
on my nerves.
And and it led to me getting terminated
along with like
11 other people, right? And
that became the the awakening of
shifting into human resources, cuz I'm
like, I'm never going to be in this type
of situation again. But, what I found is
is that you will always be in that type
of situation because
people think that they are smarter than
you, better than you, all of these
different things. People feel like when
they are right, they have permission to
do what they want to do, how they want
to do it, when they want to do it. You
understand? So,
when people say that HR is not your
friend, it's because I know for a fact
as a person that has been in HR that
there are instances in which I have put
myself in the line of fire for people in
defense of them because of my own bad
experience and it has yielded my own
adverse outcomes. It ends up being a
waste of time because the truth is is
that there's some people that have
perfected having a problem.
And so if you make it a point to stand
in people that are good at having an
issue, you're just going to be a
adopting the issues
that they have.
And for what?
I hate to say it like that cuz once upon
a time I wanted to believe that there
was a version of coming in and doing the
right thing, the happily ever after,
right? Like one day you're going to do
all of the things and you you make the
right choices and you'll come across the
right team, the right people and so on
and so forth. Everything's going to be
fine. But what did what did he say in
The Dark Knight? It's either you die a
hero or you live long enough to see
yourself become the villain. So, in
essence, here I am, right? I've gotten
to a point where I'm like, I'm not
playing with nobody's kids. I'm not
playing with nobody's kids. Like yo, you
got a problem, you going to have to tell
me how to fix it cuz I've been in too
many situations where people got issue,
people wanted to do this, they want to
do that, they don't know how to do it,
but they're telling you that you're
doing something wrong, all kind of [ __ ]
where I'm just getting pulled and tugged
by people that don't know what they're
doing, but they're fixed
on having a problem.
So, here we are.
We're hiring some folks.
So now, I've been around the block with
this work [ __ ] for a while now, right?
Like I've been doing this for a long
time. I'm a person that takes work
pretty seriously. I have a pretty good
phone response and this is the thing
that I call like hyper-vigilance that I
tell y'all about all the time. And um
because of that, I pay very close
attention to a lot of things.
So, recently I had
uh
>> [snorts]
>> I work with
>> [laughter]
>> And [ __ ] it. So, I work with this uh
with this cockeyed [ __ ] right?
>> [laughter]
>> And shorty kind of like
she's a person that you could tell
that she's used to being the center of
attention,
right?
So,
she's the kind of person that if you
don't notice her or you don't pay her
any attention, she assumes that you
don't like her.
And now the problem with people
and their presumptions of not being
liked, they believe that not being liked
also means that people will be an
antagonist.
When in all actuality, that's not true,
right? A long time ago I did a video and
I compared blueberries to strawberries
and talking about like honestly, I think
this video I made in like 2018 or 2019
or some [ __ ] like that.
I don't like blueberries as much as I
like strawberries, right?
If I go into a store, I don't go into
the fruit aisle and argue with
blueberries about not being
strawberries.
I just go to the strawberries and I pick
up strawberries and I get the [ __ ] out
the store.
So, I'm a very simple person in the
sense that like yo, if I don't like you,
I probably just won't pay you any mind.
I'm not going to antagonize you. I'm
just going to stay clear.
I don't need that kind of problem in my
life,
right?
But shorty has this idea that that I not
only do I not care for her,
but how somehow she's in danger because
of that.
Bless her heart. I don't I don't know
why she thinks that.
So, she made it a thing. She made it a
fuss.
After she first made it a fuss and it
didn't work, sometime went by, kind of
just left things as they were. And very
clearly like this still ruckus or you
know, noise in the wind that apparently
I'm some sort of antagonist. Now, when I
asked like, "What do you need from me so
that this isn't an issue?"
They just say [ __ ] like, "Well, I just
don't understand why you don't like me."
And I'm like, "What the [ __ ] are we
doing? I don't I don't want to talk like
I'm not I'm not your friend. I don't
know you. I don't I'm not your friend.
I'm not your friend." Don't ask me to be
friends and I don't want to be friends.
This is weird.
All right.
Some time go by.
And it's in the past. It's like uh I
think we're past it, right? Mhm. Frog.
Shorty come through and like uh at some
point
a friend pull up.
And her friend is being brought in
as
as the teeth.
Right? So, the the conversation is is
that we need someone that's more
aggressive. While I'm on the back end
and it's like, "Yeah."
"Don't don't try to try to be nice when
you talk to people." I'm like, "All
right, whatever."
It happens, right?
Uh so, they need this
this more intimidating figure.
So, she comes in and she takes to the
bit pretty
pretty s- pretty aggressively, right?
Like she takes to it and she's like,
"Yeah, like I'm showing up." And I
notice that she got a tendency to talk a
certain type of way.
I'm like, "Sarah,
water off a duck's back. Let that It
doesn't matter."
So, this is a particular window of time
in which we have to work together. So,
there are a series of incidences that
occur.
With Shorty,
it's it's kind of project management
style. I do one part, somebody do the
next part, somebody do the next part,
somebody do the next part. And once we
get there, it comes back to me and I
finalize the steps.
>> [snorts]
>> Go ahead.
And I notice something interesting.
The the the cockeyed one
had a issue, right? Or not Better yet,
not had an issue, but fulfilled the duty
at a very odd time.
And because they are so attention
starved or attention centered, like, oh,
just see me and how great I am and how
hard I work.
They notified that they had completed
this task at an unusual time.
And I peeped it and I'm like, I'm going
to sit that in my back pocket because
that's another task that I would end up
having to take ownership of.
It's like, that's interesting.
Following day,
the new friend the new friend comes in
and is like, oh, Sabrina, did you do X,
Y, and Z? And I'm like, uh, here go that
tone again.
I'll have it in a minute.
And then throughout the day, every
couple hours,
they ask the same question.
And so at some point, I stopped
answering them cuz I'm like, yeah,
you're you're actually being ridiculous
because this particular task takes
several hours to do. This is not
something This is a typical This is a
typical two-day kind of task. But for
me,
I'll get it done in a day.
In addition to some other things that I
got to do.
Then the director of these two people
come in and say, oh, it's me that's
asking.
So [snorts] at this point,
I'm annoyed, but now I see the game.
So I'm like, all right, bet.
I take it and I'm like, yo, you're all
set cuz I was finishing up, right? Like
it was like another 20, 30 minutes.
I'm like, yo, you're all set. You do
what you got to do.
So the cockeyed friend and the new
friend
work together on this next part of the
task.
And what took me
I had to go through
about 400 items,
right?
And passed off
68 for them.
What took me about 7 hours to do
by myself,
they took about five and a half as a
unit
to clean up together.
And similarly to that cockeyed friend at
that odd time of sending a notification,
this new friend
goes ahead and sends a notification at
an odd time and mentioned that her and
her cockeyed friend had done it
together. And I'm like, "Hmm.
That's interesting."
Next day comes.
So, there's another part of this process
that happens and you it usually has
a several-day turnover.
Day comes and goes and following morning
rolls around.
And this new friend,
any updates?
He's like, "Yeah.
There's plenty of stuff going on."
He's like, "Well, I find it funny how
this is the the new friend." I find it
funny that we didn't have this and we
didn't have that and we didn't have
this. And I was like, "Excuse me.
So that we are clear,
you just pulled off this work yesterday.
Stop [ __ ] playing with me." In so
many words.
>> [snorts]
>> Then there's this retreat and the
director is actually inside of this
thread.
Like,
watching everything but not saying
anything. And then when I start to bite,
now it's a "Oh, no. It's just
I just need this information for X, Y,
and Z." So, I'm like, "Oh, it comes and
it goes." The week ends cuz I'm like,
"Yeah, it's whatever. I don't care." And
I'm [ __ ] livid because I don't like
people talking to me crazy.
But it happens.
Monday comes around. I'm talking to
to a chief.
We meet in the morning. He's like, "Yo,
how's things going?" It's great weekend,
blah, blah, blah. Now, this is where it
gets interesting. He's like, "Everything
good?" Everything is good.
He go about his business.
Next day come and go. I'm like, "It's
it's now Tuesday."
And so, he's like, "Yo, can I have a
conversation with you?" So, I'mma be
very honest with y'all.
That can we talk thing, like that's
that's an issue for me. So, I start to
have a full-blown like
panic reaction.
And I was like, "Oh, no, like the ghosts
of my past are erupting right now
because he's asking for a meeting at an
all time." Meetings at all time usually
means something sinister is going on.
But, we won't wait and see.
After sitting around, he calls me up, we
get on, and we start talking. And he
asked me about this situation.
And then when I talked to him,
the conversation looks a little
interesting, right? Like
he's like, "Yo, you know, you He's like,
"You didn't say anything." I'm just
like, "Yo, cuz it wasn't a big deal."
Genuinely. I was like, "I was annoyed."
But, I don't argue with stupid people.
It's a waste of my time cuz remember, if
I don't like you, I just don't deal with
you. I reduce my interactions with you.
Tell me what you need. And I'mma pass
you exactly what you asked
[clears throat] for.
So, he's like, "Yeah, but you didn't say
anything. You didn't just" I was like,
"Yeah, cuz I don't want this." This is
what we call a hostile work environment.
For what? We work remote. I'm in my
crib.
I'm not about to have a hard time with
people that I don't know, that I don't
deal with, that don't cut my checks,
that I don't break bread with, nothing
like that.
This is a moment.
Long story complicated, in us going back
and forth,
I explained to him that I believe I
said, "It sounds like
when you speak to me,
I become urgent. When you speak to them,
they become fearful.
And it creates a response
that doesn't match even though we are
attempting to achieve the same thing."
He said, "Oh,
that actually makes a lot of sense."
So, I'm like, "Yeah."
My goal is
not to respond to things from a fearful
place, but to get things done as
efficiently and as effectively as
possible.
We are at a point now where we are
operating inside of this project
and for all of the points of contacts
that we have made,
I still cannot tell you, nor can they
tell you, what is the thing that they
are looking for so that we can pinpoint
and isolate
what is most likely to represent the
thing that we are looking for.
And I'm like, that's just the nature of
it. So, if we are shooting in the dark,
if we are looking for a needle in a
haystack, we just have to understand
this is going to take longer, naturally,
because again, we have failed to
identify what it is that we are looking
for. We are going through this process
hoping to find the thing that feels
right and feels good. Literally, this is
what's happening.
And while we walked away from that
conversation with a clearer and better
understanding of one another, and I've
noticed a change in the approach of the
cockeyed one and her friend,
something that was important about that
interaction
is something I've been sitting with.
Essentially,
their interaction and what they did,
it was the perfect example of
triangulation.
Like, I think that it is not Is it
dolphins
or sharks? Killer whales. It It's killer
whales. When killer whales are looking
for
a seal, right?
When they
jump in and they are going to attack a
seal,
they kind of triangulate them.
They put them in a situation where if
the seal comes off of this little block
of ice at any point, they got no shot.
Right? It's kind of like when dolphins
take out a shark, too, right? Like they
do this thing where they flip them
upside down, and when they flip them, a
shark has no capacity to orient itself
once they are back
down belly down, right?
And it was that moment that I was like,
"Oh, these [ __ ] was trying to create
a situation in which
I have no excuse for why I didn't do
something.
Uh
I'm I'm poorly communicative, and all of
these things would circumstantially make
sense
if I wasn't a [ __ ] that was just like,
"I'm doing my work and I'm not paying
you [ __ ] no mind."
But ultimately, I noticed what you did.
And these are managers of people, and I
feel for people that work with or are
led by people like this.
Because when they don't like you,
they start to create an idea about you
and set up a series of circumstances to
make that idea about you true even
though you did not participate in
anything that's inappropriate. Does that
make sense?
And this is the first time
that I've sat back and I peeped it, and
I said to myself,
"These are some [ __ ] I would beat
them the [ __ ] up if I had the chance."
Yeah.
And what's so crazy is that the [ __ ]
eyed [ __ ]
she got mixed babies.
Her man of choice
looks like us.
Ain't that something?
And I've been sitting with this
and and bubbling, ruminating, if you
will,
what happened and what it means.
And in essence, I'm now scanning on a
consistent basis of who's a threat.
And then I thought about
why isn't my misery enough?
So, why would I sit here and go back and
forth with this [ __ ] worried about
people
and what they got going on?
My misery is enough. I don't need to be
frustrated, annoyed, going back and
forth, thinking about all this because
I'm not here to give you a hard time.
Why are you going out of your way to
give me a hard time?
People that perfect having a problem.
It's one of those things, but what's
worse than that is how many different
places that mindset shows up.
>> [snorts]
>> My little YouTube channel
that's generated maybe 50 something
dollars,
literally.
1,800 subscribers that I appreciate cuz
when I think about the idea of over a
thousand people being interested in what
I have to say, I still am stunned about
the magnitude of that.
But comparatively
most people will say that that's not a
big deal.
Somehow, someway still
I have people
that come into my space
and say crazy [ __ ] like
have you ever been
famous or dealt with somebody that has
money like Dame Dash?
People say that I made up or like my
vaccine injection was
>> [laughter]
>> was liquid experiment or some something
like that.
It was another time a young lady
jumped on the comment that I made and
said um
y'all be so quick to throw around mental
health disorders
and name five of nine of these symptoms
and so on and so forth.
I think with that young lady though,
like she made the comment and happened
to click my profile and then saw
that I wasn't just making a comment,
she deleted it.
But I'mma share it anyway.
But there are people that perfect having
a problem. So I guess another part of
this conversation that I want to mention
is a long time ago I I made a I think
the first video I made
was about the root word of motivation is
mot and m o t means movement.
And the idea that sometimes you will
move mobilize people, create movement in
people that does not look positive
towards you.
The notion of the anti anything
is proof of that. People will be
mobilized
being against you.
And but you got to be tough enough to
say
I don't give a [ __ ] about nothing you
talking about.
But I don't know.
Know the difference between somebody
that is perfectly content with having a
problem
and if it's worth engagement cuz
otherwise
you will burn out and be frustrated
by the insatiability of someone that is
dead set on not being satisfied.
I'll talk to y'all later.